<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ~</title>
    <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ~</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 03:58:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://geekodour.xyz/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do College Matter?</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/do-college-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 03:58:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/do-college-matter/</guid>
      <description>Archive post from my newsletter. letter #1
 Dear reader,
This is my first letter from my newsletter indication. I created this newsletter a year ago, but never felt ready enough to send out a letter. Waiting for the perfect moment can wait now. ;)
This is my newsletter and not my twitter, so I&amp;rsquo;ll blast my subjective perceptions to space here. (that&amp;rsquo;s the nicest word I could find for my shitty opinions), I am also bad at writing and known for making a lot of grammatical mistakes, I no longer make spelling mistakes, thanks to the pointy red lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anecdotes about nice people and my summer internship at rtCamp, Pune</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/rtcamp-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 19:45:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/rtcamp-story/</guid>
      <description>Long-time posting here! I spent half of my summer at rtCamp this year as a systems intern and I had an amazing time there, learned a lot, made good friends, mentors but most importantly returned with a much clearer idea about how nice people can be, this idea really inspires me to be a better person so here it goes, hope it inspires you too in some way or the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC&#39;19 Report - CNCF/Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/gsoc19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 19:01:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/gsoc19/</guid>
      <description>This blogpost summarizes the work done by me in the summer of 2019 as part of Google Summer of Code under the organization CNCF/Prometheus, I plan to keep contributing to Prometheus as a regular contributor after GSoC period.
 Huge thanks Krasi Georgiev(Mentor) for being extremely helpful and supportive throughout this SoC. Most of the changes mentioned in this blogpost are not deployed to prombench.prometheus.io yet
 Some silly Prometheus metrics, just for fun 😃 :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on WiFi and the wireless subsystem on Linux</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/wifi-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 16:42:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/wifi-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quite sometime since I posted anything proper on the internet, but recently I was reading about how WiFi is deployed in enterprise and the wireless subsystem in the Linux kernel. So I thought it would be nice to have a self note about it in form of a short blogpost.
Table of contents  Wireless communication How our machines connect to our WNICs  Wireless communication A WNIC can operate in two ways:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exec family - A quick note</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/exec-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 16:40:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/exec-family/</guid>
      <description>This is just for personal future reference:
There is a family of exec() library functions, all of which have slightly different characteristics:
int execl ( const char *path, const char *arg, ... ); int execlp( const char *file, const char *arg, ... ); int execle( const char *path, const char *arg, ..., char *const envp[] ); int execv ( const char *path, char *const argv[] ); int execvp( const char *file, char *const argv[] ); int execvpe(const char *file, char *const argv[], char *const envp[]);   if p in the name: accepts a program name and it searches for the program in $PATH env var if l or v in the name: the program name must be given in full(path).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH to VM hangs and takes a long time to log in</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/ssh-slows-gssapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 02:44:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/ssh-slows-gssapi/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to learn ansible and I got quite frustrated at how long(15s) is it taking for my ubuntu vm to ssh into my centos vm. So to know why is it taking so i used ssh vagrant@ip_addr -vvv to print things in debug mode.
The debug messages were these (trimmed ofc)
debug1: Unspecified GSS failure. Minor code may provide more information No Kerberos credentials available debug1: Unspecified GSS failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fsf Internship Part 1</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/fsf-intern-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 03:39:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/fsf-intern-p1/</guid>
      <description>Link to fsf intro blogpost at the fsf blog: https://www.fsf.org/blogs/sysadmin/introducing-hrishikesh-barman-intern-with-the-fsf-tech-team
The most exciting thing about this internship(other the learning part) was the moment when I was talking to RMS over the phone. life is complete now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning new tech</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/learnging-new-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 13:23:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/learnging-new-tech/</guid>
      <description>This is an approach that can be done, I don&amp;rsquo;t follow it yet but will fedenitely try it. Also, this post is not about how to learn new technology.
For example you want to start learning redis or maybe netfilter,
These softwares have their conferences, as you learn you can also apply for these</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character encoding bits</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/character_encoding_bits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 10:04:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/character_encoding_bits/</guid>
      <description>So I was just hanging around a discord group when someone asked this:
 What&amp;rsquo;s the minimum number of bits I can use to encode an arbitrary ASCII string 8 characters long that only contains capital letters and numbers? I&amp;rsquo;m coming up with 42, but that seems like too many. Maybe my intuition for this is just wrong
 So how did he come up with 42?
He&amp;rsquo;s basically asking he as a set of 36 possibilities for a character (26+10) and the length of the string he wants to fit those characters in is 8 characters long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a bot to post Instagram stories automatically to my blog</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/building-a-bot-to-post-instagram-stories-automatically-to-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 02:44:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/building-a-bot-to-post-instagram-stories-automatically-to-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; Made a bot that posts selected instagram stories automatically to my blog.
Source Code is here if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for that.
I love instagram. I like posting stories and memes there and yesteday night I felt the urgency(ironical) to post about education on my story.
I wrote a moderately long post in a story with small text. I realized this should&amp;rsquo;ve been a blogpost aswell but I already posted the story and to get the text back I&amp;rsquo;ve to do OCR on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to git squash quickly without messing up</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/how-to-git-squash-quickly-without-messing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 08:00:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/how-to-git-squash-quickly-without-messing-up/</guid>
      <description>So you have a branch with few commits and you want to squash all of them into one before sending a PR to your favorite opensource project.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it.
First do,
$ git log  Scroll till you reach the upstream or origin branch commit where the current branch was branched from. Then just copy the commitid of that commit. If you branched it from the master then it will either be (upstream/master, master) or (origin/master, master) i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I am planning to make my Meme and Music bots</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/how-i-am-planning-to-make-my-meme-and-music-bots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 04:24:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/how-i-am-planning-to-make-my-meme-and-music-bots/</guid>
      <description>So i want this to be a hack, it does not matter if other people will be able to use it(should be able to though) but it should somehow work for me.
Github gives unlimited storage, so all images will be uploaded to the blog github repo.
Meme bot for video and images Use hosts file to make url short for heroku app. There will be a simple webapp where you can just put links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World Blogpost</title>
      <link>https://geekodour.xyz/post/hello-world-blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 02:44:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://geekodour.xyz/post/hello-world-blogpost/</guid>
      <description>So, welcome to my blog! This is probably my 5th or 6th blog but I&amp;rsquo;ve spent about 4-6 hours making this one. So this one probably will fly off. Let&amp;rsquo;s see.
Also, will be blogging regularly but not daily ofcourse.
c
printf(&amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;);  python
print(Hello World!)  works.
nice.
./Lots of love &amp;lt;3</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>