<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ~</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ~</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 03:39:35 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fsf Internship Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/fsf-intern-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 03:39:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fsf-intern-p1/</guid>
      <description>It all started when I was looking for some</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning new tech</title>
      <link>/post/learnging-new-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 13:23:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learnging-new-tech/</guid>
      <description>This is an approach that can be done, I don&amp;rsquo;t follow it yet but will fedenitely try it. Also, this post is not about how to learn new technology.
For example you want to start learning redis or maybe netfilter,
These softwares have their conferences, as you learn you can also apply for these</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character encoding bits</title>
      <link>/post/character_encoding_bits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 10:04:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/character_encoding_bits/</guid>
      <description>So I was just hanging around a discord group when someone asked this:
 What&amp;rsquo;s the minimum number of bits I can use to encode an arbitrary ASCII string 8 characters long that only contains capital letters and numbers? I&amp;rsquo;m coming up with 42, but that seems like too many. Maybe my intuition for this is just wrong
 So how did he come up with 42?
He&amp;rsquo;s basically asking he as a set of 36 possibilities for a character (26+10) and the length of the string he wants to fit those characters in is 8 characters long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of problems in education</title>
      <link>/post/education-problem-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 23:09:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/education-problem-list/</guid>
      <description>This is just to note down my ideas about current problems in the Indian education system. This is not exhaustime and will always keep growing. I hope it shrinks someday.
There can be another blogpost on what I think the ideal Indian education system would look like. I am not knowlegable enough to write something like that but as I collect enough sharable information and ideas I&amp;rsquo;ll write one post on it someday, eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Update 28 June 2018</title>
      <link>/post/life-juneend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/life-juneend/</guid>
      <description>So last month I did a couple of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a bot to post Instagram stories automatically to my blog</title>
      <link>/post/building-a-bot-to-post-instagram-stories-automatically-to-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 02:44:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-a-bot-to-post-instagram-stories-automatically-to-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; Made a bot that posts selected instagram stories automatically to my blog.
Source Code is here if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for that.
I love instagram. I like posting stories and memes there and yesteday night I felt the urgency(ironical) to post about education on my story.
I wrote a moderately long post in a story with small text. I realized this should&amp;rsquo;ve been a blogpost aswell but I already posted the story and to get the text back I&amp;rsquo;ve to do OCR on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to git squash quickly without messing up</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-git-squash-quickly-without-messing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 08:00:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-git-squash-quickly-without-messing-up/</guid>
      <description>So you have a branch with few commits and you want to squash all of them into one before sending a PR to your favorite opensource project.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it.
First do,
$ git log  Scroll till you reach the upstream or origin branch commit where the current branch was branched from. Then just copy the commitid of that commit. If you branched it from the master then it will either be (upstream/master, master) or (origin/master, master) i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I am planning to make my Meme and Music bots</title>
      <link>/post/how-i-am-planning-to-make-my-meme-and-music-bots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 04:24:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-am-planning-to-make-my-meme-and-music-bots/</guid>
      <description>So i want this to be a hack, it does not matter if other people will be able to use it(should be able to though) but it should somehow work for me.
Github gives unlimited storage, so all images will be uploaded to the blog github repo.
Meme bot for video and images Use hosts file to make url short for heroku app. There will be a simple webapp where you can just put links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World Blogpost</title>
      <link>/post/hello-world-blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 02:44:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hello-world-blogpost/</guid>
      <description>So, welcome to my blog! This is probably my 5th or 6th blog but I&amp;rsquo;ve spent about 4-6 hours making this one. So this one probably will fly off. Let&amp;rsquo;s see.
Also, will be blogging regularly but not daily ofcourse.
c
printf(&amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;);  python
print(Hello World!)  works.
nice.
./Lots of love &amp;lt;3</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>